Dali Hillary

Complex problem-solver with analytical and driven mindset. Dedicated to achieving demanding development objectives according to tight schedules while producing the right and optimized solutions, and with complete understanding of the entire software development lifecycle for 9 years down the road.

Bukoto Street,
Kampala Uganda
256 751-028-655
256 760-087-659
dalirichardh@gmail.com
https://github.com/dalihillary
https://ug.linkedin.com/in/da
li-hillary-031b2b219

EXPERIENCE

Aspen Technologies LTD, Kampala — Associate Software Engineer

2022-07 - Current

- Collaborated with teams to analyze system solutions based on client requirements.
- Directed teams completing regression tests to support successful product development stages.
- Teamed with business analysts to deliver high-availability solutions for mission-critical applications.
- Collaborated with product owners to stay current on intended functionality.
- Tested troubleshooting methods and documented resolutions for inclusion in the knowledge base for support team use.
- Gather requirements and perform gap analysis through design workshops with users.

Asterisk International Group LTD, Kampala — Associate Software Engineer

2021-12 - 2022-02

- Teamed with business analysts to deliver high-availability solutions for mission-critical applications.
- Developed ERP projects using laravel framework and nodejs.
- Checked configuration files and logs to uncover root causes of problems.
- Created successful test scripts to manage automated feature testing,
- Improved systems with addition of new features and infrastructure.
- Educated stakeholders on data protection tactics to reduce breaches.
- Installed system updates to address vulnerabilities and reduce security issues.

SKILLS

Leadership.
Communication.
Problem Solving.
Innovation and Creativity

AWARDS

Winner of the 2022 Innovate for Ability hackathon in Nkumba University

2nd place Women in Fintech Hackathon 2022

TECHNICAL PROFILE

C, Python, Javascript, MySQL, Git, C++, Nodejs, Laravel, Php, Linux, Express, PostgreSQL, Kotlin, Java, Android, Django, Reactjs, APIs, Electronjs, ReactNative, Flutter

JIT Innovation Hub, Jinja — Associate Software Engineer

2021-07 - 2021-11

- Supported development, QA and user experience staff to develop new products.
- Developed ERP projects using laravel framework.
- Learned software engineering process improvements and best practices.
- Wrote clear, clean code for various projects.
- Partnered with team members to learn best practices in software design.

Magezi Solutions, Kampala — Software Developer

2020-04 - 2020-11

- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Documented technical workflows and knowledge to educate newly hired employees.
- Participated in software field testing to verify performance of developed projects.
- Translated customer requirements into written use cases.
- Designed customized solutions for proposals to potential customers.

Competencies

Algorithm implementation,
Testing and maintenance,
Client requirements, Team
reporting, Software
documentation, software
deployment, Programming
best practices, Database
programming and modeling,
REST API, MVVM, MVC, MVI,
MVP, Security
considerations, Agile, Scrum,
pentesting (Ethical hacking)

LANGUAGES

English, Luganda

Hideout Bar and Lounge, Kampala — Head of Maintenance

2018-01 - 2018-08

- Worked frequently with mechanical and plumbing systems to complete knowledgeable inspections and skilled repairs.
- Monitored priorities and liaised between maintenance team and management, delegating tasks to complete on time.
- Created and implemented maintenance program to optimize operational efficiency and reduce downtime.
- Developed and implemented building operations and maintenance policies.
- Delegated tasks to carefully selected employees in alignment with resource management goals.

Hilson Bags And Craft Work, Kampala — Salesman

2016-11 - 2017-02

- Showcased product features to customers and discussed technical details to overcome objections and lock in sales.
- Visited customer locations to evaluate requirements, demonstrate product offerings and propose strategic solutions for diverse needs.
- Used consultative sales techniques to understand customer needs and recommend relevant products and services.
- Met with existing customers and prospects to discuss business needs and recommend optimal solutions.

EDUCATION

Makerere University, Kampala, Uganda — Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering: Embedded Systems, Requirements Engineering, Security

2018-08 - 2022-11

Kisaasi College School, Kampala, Uganda — *Uganda Advanced Certificate Of Education: Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, Computer*

2016-02 - 2017-12

Kisaasi College School, Kampala, Uganda — *Uganda Certificate Of Education*

2012-02 - 2015-11

Makindye Junior School, Kampala, Uganda — *Primary Leaving Education*

2006-02 - 2011-11

PROJECTS

AIDA (Smart Academic Personal Assistant) — An automated system using whatsapp platform that integrates with e-learning platforms

CVAS (Eyes for the blind) — A low-cost smart assistive devices to help the visually impaired navigate, find objects of interest and read non-braille text

Business Solutions — I have worked on multiple solutions aimed at improving business processes in various organizations.

RatComet — An advanced android Spyware / Security Tool providing surveillance on all device activities remotely from a Web Admin Control Panel.

- Developed using Kotlin and Laravel from scratch
- This tool was **not** made public since it could be misused

More on github (https://github.com/DALIHILLARY)

REFERENCES

Dr. Mary Nsabagwa

Researcher & Lecturer College Of Computing Makerere University

Tel: 256 701 124 388

Mr. Innocent Kawooya

CEO, HiPipo

Tel: 256 779 345 331

Mr. Ojara Timothy

Head Legal Affairs Higher Education Students' Financing Board (HESFB)

Tel: 256 772 563 635

Mr. Mugabi Samuel

Director Directorate of ICT Support Makerere University

Tel: 256 751 942 581